<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Amyloid on The Portal of Knowledge</title>
    <link>https://alamot.github.io/tags/amyloid/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Amyloid on The Portal of Knowledge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alamot.github.io/tags/amyloid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A consensus method for the prediction of aggregation-prone peptides in globular proteins</title>
      <link>https://alamot.github.io/amylpred2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alamot.github.io/amylpred2/</guid>
      <description>My Bachelor&#39;s thesis in Biology was about developing a consensus method for the prediction of amyloidogenic determinants in globular proteins. Several studies suggest that not all regions of a polypeptide chain are equally important for determining its aggregation tendency. It seems that protein aggregation is mediated by short aggregation prone segments. These aggregation nucleating regions can be detected in the sequence of a protein in silico based on physicochemical principles (phenomenological models) or/and molecular simulation approaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amyloid fibrils (available in greek only)</title>
      <link>https://alamot.github.io/amyloids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alamot.github.io/amyloids/</guid>
      <description>Σύντομη ιστορική αναδρομή Η λέξη «αμυλοειδές» επινοήθηκε αρχικά (1838) από τον βοτανολόγο Matthias Jakob Schleiden1, από την ελληνική λέξη «άμυλον», για να περιγράψει φυσιολογικά αμυλώδη συστατικά των φυτών. Το 1854, ο Rudolf Ludwig Carl Virchow2 χρησιμοποίησε τον όρο για να δηλώσει μακροσκοπικές ανωμαλίες σε ανθρώπινους ιστούς (όπως τα «corpora amylacea» στον εγκέφαλο, οι «στεατώδεις» εναποθέσεις που εντοπίζονταν στο ήπαρ και ο «κηρώδης» σπλήνας), που βάφονταν μπλε με διάλυμα ιωδίου και μωβ με τη προσθήκη πυκνού θειικού οξέος3, επειδή πίστευε ότι είχαν υποστεί «κυτταρινομεταμόρφωση».</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>