<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Puzzles on The Portal of Knowledge</title>
    <link>https://alamot.github.io/tags/puzzles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Puzzles on The Portal of Knowledge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alamot.github.io/tags/puzzles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Retriever of Lost Dreams</title>
      <link>https://alamot.github.io/rold/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alamot.github.io/rold/</guid>
      <description>Your name is Rold. You live in a very special place in the Universe. This place is called Dreamland. Your job is to foster and guard the Dream Stars. For, from their stardust, the people&#39;s dreams are born.
For a long time, everything was running smoothly and you loved your job. But one day, an evil Force stole all the Dream Stars from Dreamland and hid them in a castle with many rooms, full of traps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alamot&#39;s matchstick puzzles</title>
      <link>https://alamot.github.io/matchsticks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alamot.github.io/matchsticks/</guid>
      <description>This is a game with matchstick puzzles I created in 2014.
Αυτό είναι ένα παιχνίδι με σπαζοκεφαλιές σπίρτων που δημιούργησα το 2014.
FeaturesΧαρακτηριστικά 100 awesome matchstick puzzles! Can you solve them all?  Great variety of categories Puzzles with movement, removal or rotation of matchsticks Solve geometry problems Form squares, triangles, rectangles, rhombi and other shapes Divide figures into identical parts Change the total surface Transform shapes Multiply objects Correct math equations Find the word problems Solve riddles ★ Bonus ★: Under the instructions for each puzzle, there are various history facts, fun facts, trivia, quotes, proverbs, poems and even short stories about matches!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>