<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Genome on The Portal of Knowledge</title>
    <link>https://alamot.github.io/tags/genome/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Genome on The Portal of Knowledge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alamot.github.io/tags/genome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The organism with the smallest genome and proteome</title>
      <link>https://alamot.github.io/smallest_genome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alamot.github.io/smallest_genome/</guid>
      <description>QuestionΕρώτημα Which organism has the smallest genome and proteome size?
Ποιός είναι άραγε ο οργανισμός εκείνος που έχει το μικρότερο γονιδίωμα και πρωτέωμα;
We have to make it clear that by saying the &#34;smallest genome&#34; we mean the smallest genome of a free-living organism. Because there are viruses or even prokaryotes with extremely small genomes, but these organisms live as obligate endosymbionts or obligate parasites. That is, they depend heavily on their host to support their vital functions and, therefore, a lot of their genes have been lost due to lack of necessity (or maybe they did not have many of those genes in the first place).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genome: A dynamic information source (available in greek only)</title>
      <link>https://alamot.github.io/dynamic_genome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alamot.github.io/dynamic_genome/</guid>
      <description>Εισαγωγή Οι πληροφορίες που απαιτούνται για τη δημιουργία, την ανάπτυξη και τη συντήρηση ενός οργανισμού αποθηκεύονται στην αλληλουχία των νουκλεοτιδίων του DNA. Το γενετικό υλικό, τόσο των προκαρυωτικών όσο και των ευκαρυωτικών οργανισμών, είναι αυτό που -σε συνεργασία με το περιβάλλον- καθορίζει τον φαινότυπο του ατόμου. Έτσι, οι γενετικές πληροφορίες αντιγράφονται με υψηλό βαθμό πιστότητας, ώστε να μεταβιβάζονται ακέραιες στους απογόνους ενός κυττάρου. Παρόλα αυτά, το DNA δεν παραμένει αμετάβλητο.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>