<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Upload on The Portal of Knowledge</title>
    <link>https://alamot.github.io/tags/upload/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Upload on The Portal of Knowledge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alamot.github.io/tags/upload/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MSSQL shell with file upload capability</title>
      <link>https://alamot.github.io/mssql_shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alamot.github.io/mssql_shell/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes we can get access to a Microsoft SQL server in which the execution of the xp_cmdshell stored procedure is allowed but other kind of traffic (TCP, UDP, ICMP et.c.) is blocked by some kind of firewall. This can make the acquisition of a shell more difficult. In such cases, it would be useful to have a kind of shell via multiple xp_cmdshell commands. One problem with that approach is that every xp_cmdshell command will be executed in a new context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WinRM shell (a.k.a. PowerShell Remoting) with file upload capability</title>
      <link>https://alamot.github.io/winrm_shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alamot.github.io/winrm_shell/</guid>
      <description>According to Microsoft, PowerShell Remoting is the recommended way to manage Windows systems. PowerShell Remoting uses Windows Remote Management (WinRM), which is the Microsoft implementation of the Web Services for Management (WS-Management) protocol, to allow users to run PowerShell commands on remote computers. But can we make use of it (i.e. connect) from a Linux machine?
Σύμφωνα με την Microsoft, το PowerShell Remoting είναι ο ενδεδειγμένος τρόπος για την απομακρυσμένη διαχείριση Windows συστημάτων.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>