<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microbe on The Portal of Knowledge</title>
    <link>https://alamot.github.io/tags/microbe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microbe on The Portal of Knowledge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alamot.github.io/tags/microbe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The organism with the smallest genome and proteome</title>
      <link>https://alamot.github.io/smallest_genome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alamot.github.io/smallest_genome/</guid>
      <description>QuestionΕρώτημα Which organism has the smallest genome and proteome size?
Ποιός είναι άραγε ο οργανισμός εκείνος που έχει το μικρότερο γονιδίωμα και πρωτέωμα;
We have to make it clear that by saying the &#34;smallest genome&#34; we mean the smallest genome of a free-living organism. Because there are viruses or even prokaryotes with extremely small genomes, but these organisms live as obligate endosymbionts or obligate parasites. That is, they depend heavily on their host to support their vital functions and, therefore, a lot of their genes have been lost due to lack of necessity (or maybe they did not have many of those genes in the first place).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brucellosis (available in greek only)</title>
      <link>https://alamot.github.io/brucellosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alamot.github.io/brucellosis/</guid>
      <description>Εισαγωγή Η βρουκέλλωση (γνωστή επίσης και με τα ονόματα «μελιταίος πυρετός» ή «πυρετός της Μάλτας» ή «πυρετός του Γιβραλτάρ» ή «πυρετός της Κύπρου» ή «πυρετός της Μεσογείου» ή «κυματοειδής πυρετός του Bang») είναι μια ζωονόσος που οφείλεται στις βρουκέλλες.
Οι βρουκέλλες είναι βακτηρίδια, αρκετά ανθεκτικά, που μπορούν να ζήσουν από 4 εώς 10 εβδομάδες στα γαλακτοκομικά προϊόντα, στο νερό και στην κοπριά. Είναι παθογόνα τόσο για τον άνθρωπο όσο και για τα ζώα.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>