<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Parasite on The Portal of Knowledge</title>
    <link>https://alamot.github.io/tags/parasite/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Parasite on The Portal of Knowledge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alamot.github.io/tags/parasite/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind control parasites. How do they do it?</title>
      <link>https://alamot.github.io/mindcontrol_parasites/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alamot.github.io/mindcontrol_parasites/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that there are parasites that can manipulate the behavior of their host organism? The hairworms is such an example. Hairworms are long thin wormlike parasites. Their scientific name is Nematomorpha. They parasite mostly on insects, like crickets for example. Crickets are living on the land but hairworms can reproduce only in water. Therefore, hairworms have to «drive» their host towards water bodies. Most times this results in the death of the host because crickets get drawn themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entomopathogenic fungi (available in greek only)</title>
      <link>https://alamot.github.io/entomopathogenic_fungi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alamot.github.io/entomopathogenic_fungi/</guid>
      <description>Εισαγωγή Ένας εντομοπαθογόνος μύκητας είναι ένας μύκητας που λειτουργεί ως παράσιτο των εντόμων. Στις περισσότερες περιπτώσεις η προσβολή έχει ως αποτέλεσμα το θάνατο ή τη σοβαρή βλάβη του εντόμου ξενιστή. Πρόκειται δηλαδή για, ως επί το πλείστον, νεκροτροφικά παράσιτα.
Agostino Bassi
(1773-1856)  Ο Ιταλός βιολόγος Agostino Bassi (de Lodi), συγγενής και μαθητής του Lazzaro Spallanzani, θεωρείται ως ο πρώτος που έδειξε πειραματικά ότι μια ασθένεια προκαλείται από έναν μικροοργανισμό όταν, το 1835, μόλυνε μεταξοσκώληκες (Bombyx mori) με τον εντομοπαθογόνο μύκητα Beauveria bassiana.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>